Anirudh Warrier

Performance Engineer | SDET | Tech Enthusiast

Palakkad, Kerala | Email: anirudhwarrier@gmail.com | Mobile: (+91) 88-91-550070

GitHub: https://github.com/anirudhwarrier | Web: https://anirudhwarrier.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anirudhwarrier

Summary

Software engineer with 5+ years of experience, identifying and fixing performance bottlenecks in distributed eCommerce systems. Experienced in cloud technology, white box testing, agile methodology, CI/CD, Devops. Being a technology enthusiast, I am always updated with the latest trends in my field. Also an individual contributor to the in-house performance test automation framework.

Skills

Performance Testing • Performance Profiling/Engineering • Gatling • Apache JMeter • AWS • Test Automation • Python • Docker • Java • DataDog • Kibana • JIRA • Git • GitHub • Jenkins- Job DSL, Groovy • DevOps • Hashicorp Terraform IaC • White-Box Testing • Linux • Performance Tuning - PostgreSQL • Google Analytics

Professional Experience

QBurst Technologies Thrissur, Kerala
Senior Engineer October 2018 - Present (2y10m)

Lead for the Performance Engineering team, mentored and grew the team from 2 to 6 members. Understanding NFRs and defining performance test strategy. Defining performance targets and budgets. Preparing Performance Test Plan. Setting up Test Infrastructure. Evaluating load testing tools. Automation of tasks, developing scripts and tools. Performance Test Framework design for automation. Performance monitoring dashboard setup (Grafana & AWS CloudWatch)

<u>CSS Corp</u> Chennai - Tamil Nadu

Engineer - Performance Testing & Engineering

August 2016 - October 2018 (2y2m)

Part of a dedicated performance testing and engineering team. Writing Performance test cases and scenarios. Performance test scripting (LoadRunner, JMeter). Performance monitoring using APMs (NewRelic, DynaTrace). Front end optimization (WebPageTest, In-house tool) analysis. Development of in house tools and frameworks.

Projects

End To End Performance Engineering of eCommerce System Global retail giant, August 2020 - December 2020

Performance testing of eCommerce systems (REST API testing with Gatling) prior to rollout of system to a region. Load Modelling (using Google Analytics and Akamai data). Defining test scenarios. Test execution and reporting. Review meetings with the rollout team. Resolved challenges in load generation by using multi cluster load generators. Provided suggestions to solve performance bottlenecks in infrastructure settings, scaling policies (ECS, RDS, EC2) and logging system. Worked with SRE and operations to define cost effective scaling policies while ensuring optimum performance of the system, which resulted in smooth rollout.

Performance Engineering of Backend Microservices of eCommerce System

Global retail giant, January 2019 - Present

Continuous performance testing and improvement. Defining unit performance test strategy, test plan. Development of Gatling based unit performance test framework. Integration of unit performance test process into Jenkins CI/CD pipeline for continuous improvement. Improvements to Jenkins shared library. Setup of ephemeral and replicable test infrastructure using AWS EC2, ECS, Docker. On-boarding of different microservices/platforms across different languages (Java, Go, Python) for unit performance testing. Resolved challenges related to creating mocks for upstream services.

Education

University of Calicut, Aug 2012 - May 2016 | B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering | GPA 6.79/10

Certifications

IIT Madras & Great Learning, Dec. 2020 - Oct. 2021 | Advanced Certification in Software Engineering - Cloud, IoT & Blockchain

Achievements and Awards

Appreciated for effective e2e performance engagement for a major region release.

Received Hi-Flyer Award for individual contributions to the team.

QBurst, December 2020

CSS Corp, July 2017